Thomas C. Hsu

Mobile: (732) 647-5373 | Email: thomaschsu@gmail.com | Holmdel, NJ 07733 | LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/tomchsu/ | Portfolio: https://thomaschsu.github.io/

GitHub: https://github.com/thomaschsu

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Entry level Full Stack Developer with a focus on the front-end. Experienced Front-end Developer with a proven background in developing user-friendly websites and web applications. Well-versed in various programming languages including JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Node, and more. A proactive professional who enjoys systematically testing websites for bugs and debugging errors. Looking forward to applying my knowledge and expertise in web development to a like-minded company to ensure quality user interaction that produces optimal results.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, Responsive Web Design, JSON, React
- Magento 1 & 2 E-commerce
- WordPress
- Node.js, Firebase
- Express
- SEO
- MongoDB

- GIT, GitHub
- Bootstrap, Materialize
- APIs, AJAX
- CLI
- Microsoft Office Suite and Adobe Suite
- MySQL
- Heroku

APPLICATIONS BUILT

MRA International Company Website

- Front-End Developer of a team of three
- Company website that provided the world with information about MRA International
- WordPress, HTML, CSS, Graphics Design

MRA International Storefront

- Front-End Developer and Catalog manager of a team of three
- Storefront for MRA International that sold computers and electronics
- Created multiple stores for different Universities selling configured HP equipment
- Magento, HTML, CSS, Graphics Design

My Movie List

- Lead Front-End Developer of a team of five
- Designed website layout and theme
- Full Stack website for keeping track of all the movies that you have watched in your lifetime, along with a score
- React, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, Animate.css, BootStrap, Materialize, Graphics Design

Goodmovies

- Lead Front-End Developer of a team of three
- Website dedicated to finding movies based on Rotten Tomatoes ratings
- Ability to save favorite movies into Firebase
- HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Firebase, APIs, jQuery

New York Times - Search

- Lead Front-End Developer of a team of four
- A page that searches through NYT using gueries and NYT API
- HTML, CSS, JavaScript, APIs, jQuery

WORK EXPERIENCE

MRA International - Long Branch, NJ

March 2013 - February 2018

Website Administrator, Web Developer, IT Technician, Inside Sales Representative

- Took a lead role in the production and maintenance of a front-end Magento and WordPress company website to increase sales and marketing efforts.
- Built and managed graphics to boost the overall look and feel of the company websites.
- Took part in a massive company project that required imaging thousands of laptops and desktops for the Elizabeth school districts in a timely and proficient manner.
- Provided client services for malfunctioning desktops and laptops and networked with customers in addition to being an inside sales representative.

DuPont – Parlin, NJ

June 2007 - August 2007 | May 2008 - August 2008 | June 2011 - July

2011

Manufacturing Technician LSE

- Provided services in multiple team environments that assisted with the processing, inspection, and packaging of Cyrel Flexographic plates to maintain a near uptime of 90%.
- Collaborated with distribution to get products to where they needed to be in an efficient and structured way.
- Gained knowledge in patience, hard work, and how to be a team player.

EDUCATION

Rutgers University - New Brunswick, NJ

Full Stack Web Development – Coding Program

Rutgers University - New Brunswick, NJ

September 2007 – January 2012

April 2018 - October 2018

School of Arts and Sciences | School of Information Technology and Informatics | Bachelor of Arts

Major: Information Technology and Informatics

Minor: Psychology

Received Dean's List (Fall 2011)